A Guide to the Papers of Walter Scott Copeland 1880-1954
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Walter Scott Copeland 1880-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5497
This collection consists of ca. 900 items (4 Hollinger boxes; 1.5 linear shelf feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Copeland Papers were originally placed on deposit in the library on December 3, 1956, by Mr. Fillmore Norfleet of Woodbury Forrest, Virginia. The collection was given to the library by Mr. and Mrs. Fillmore Norfleet on May 5, 1980.
Biographical/Historical Information
Copeland was born on March 14, 1856, in Jackson, North Carolina, to Dr. Winfield Scott and Catherine Randolph Copeland. He was educated at a private academy and the University of Virginia from which he graduated in 1874. He married Mary A. Christian on October 13, 1885, and they had a daughter, Katherine (Mrs. Katherine C. Lacy). After the death of his first wife he married Grace B. Cunningham on April 26, 1906, and they had two children, Elizabeth Randolph (Mrs. Fillmore Norfleet) and Randolph Scott.
Copeland first worked on the staff of the Petersburg Index-Appeal in 1881. He later became the city editor of the Norfolk Virginian. In 1886 he purchased an interest in the Danville Register and served eight years as its editor, until he sold it to purchase an interest in the Richmond State. Selling it in 1896, he became a staff member of the Richmond Times, and later established the Richmond Evening Leader. In 1901, he conducted a negotiation between the Times and the Richmond Dispatch, its competing morning newspaper. These talks resulted in the consolidation of the Times and the Dispatch, into a single morning paper called the Times-Dispatch, and of their afternoon papers, the Evening Leader and the News, as an afternoon edition known as the News-Leader.
He resigned from the Times-Dispatch in 1909, purchased the Newport News Times-Herald, and moved to that city in 1911. When the Times-Herald was consolidated with the Daily Press, Copeland became president of The Daily Press, Inc., as well as publisher and editor of the Daily Press and Times-Herald. He also served four terms as president of the Virginia Press Association. Copeland died on July 24, 1928, at age seventy-two.
Scope and Content Information
This collection of Walter Scott Copeland papers consists of ca. 900 items (4 Hollinger boxes; 1.5 linear shelf feet), 1880-1954, chiefly Copeland's profesional and personal correspondence regarding his newspaper career. Also included are speeches, newspaper clippings, memorabilia, photographs, and scrapbooks.
Copeland, as editor of various Virginia newspaper, correspondend with many prominent persons concerning gubernatorial and U. S. Senate elections; race relations, particularly an incident at Hampton College in 1925 and a campaign to repeal the 14th, 15th, and 18th amendments; illiteracy; road improvements; patriotism; the Newport News shipyards; merchant marine legislation; an alleged interview that discredited Carter Glass; and numerous other subjects. Some letters deal with the financial and business aspects of the newspaper business and one undated letter gives a lengthy analysis of operations of the Newport News Daily Press. Correspondents include John Stewart Bryan, Harry F. Byrd, Sr., William Hodges Mann, Josephus Daniels, S. L. Slover, Carter Glass, Thomas Staples Martin, John Garland Pollard, Henry C. Stuart, Claude A. Swanson, and Elbert Lee Trinkle. Other correspondents include Edwin A. Alderman, James Branch Cabell, Douglas Southall Freeman, Ellen Glasgow, Louis I. Jaffe, Mary Johnston, Helen Keller, and the Newport News Chapter of the Ku Klux Klan. Copeland's correspondence also includes a topical file for the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation; there is also a file for letters, telegrams, and newspaper clippings regarding his death.
His file of speeches, addresses, and testimonials covers the period of 1919-1928. Most were written by Copeland but also included are one or two speeches written by Senator Claude Swanson and one by Senator Simeon Fess. Newspaper clippings present in the collection consist chiefly of articles written by or about Copeland, as well as miscellaneous pieces, 1908-1954. The memorabilia consists of invitations and stamps honoring the Yorktown Sesquicentennial of 1931 and covers the perios 1921-1931. Also included is a collection of photographs and prints, for the most part undated.
Of the four scrapbooks in this collection, one was kept by Mary A. Christian, Copeland's first wife, from 1880 to 1904. The second, 1895-1920, contains a pencil drawing of Copeland and the third, dated 1904, contains postcard views of Newport News, Virginia. The fourth scrapbook, 1925, pertains to a National Editorial Association trip through Virginia. There are two oversize items: one, dated 1909, certifies Copeland's membership in the Associated Press, and the other, dated 1923, appoints him a Virginia delegate to the Centennial Celebration of the Monroe Doctrine.
Organization
The collection has been arranged into six series: I. Correspondence, II. Business Memoranda and Papers re the Times-Herald, III. Speeches, Addresses, and Testimonials, IV. Miscellaneous Papers and Printed Material, V. Scrapbooks, and VI. Oversize Material.
Most of the correspondence is in individual folders in chronological order, followed by folders of miscellaneous and topical correspondence. Speeches are filed chronologically and testimonials honoring Copeland are filed in a separate folder. Series IV is divided into folders of miscellaneous papers, memorabilia, newspaper clippings, and photographs. The scrapbooks are arranged chronologically and loose items found it the scrapbooks are filed in folder directly following the books.
Additional Descriptive Data
Separated Material
The most ancient of all American commonwealths is Virginia ...[Broadside 1930 .T44 copy 1]
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - N. H. Massie to Walter Scott Copeland 1893 Apr 8 (Box 1)
  - James L. Heard to Walter Scott Copeland 1906 Apr 8 (Box 1)
  - Charles B. Cooke to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 Jan 17 (Box 1)
  - John S. Bryan to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 Mar 12 (Box 1)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 Apr 7 (Box 1)
  - Mary B. Evans to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 May 8 (Box 1)
  - Wm. Eldred to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 July 3 (Box 1)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 July 22 (Box 1)
  - S. l. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 Nov 16 (Box 1)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1908 Nov 17 (Box 1)
  - Charles H. Davis to Walter Scott Copeland 1909 Mar 26 (Box 1)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1909 Apr 16 (Box 1)
  - Furness Withy and Co., Ltd. to Times Herald1909 Aug 19 (Box 1)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1909 Sept 24 (Box 1)
  - W. E. Martz to Walter Scott Copeland 1910 Apr 19 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1910 Sep 16 (Box 1)
  - Wm. Hodges Mann to Walter Scott Copeland 1910 Sep 26 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1910 Oct 15 (Box 1)
  - R. P. Barham to Walter Scott Copeland 1910 Nov 10 (Box 1)
  - Carter Glass to Walter Scott Copeland 1911 Jan 11 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1911 Feb 18 (Box 1)
  - [Thos. S. Martin] to J. W. McCarrick (Copy) 1911 Apr 3 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1911 Apr 21 (Box 1)
  - R. S. Basham and A. A. Moss to Walter Scott Copeland 1911 Jun 12 (Box 1)
  - Mary Johnston to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1912 Apr 6 (Box 1)
  - Mary Johnston to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1912 Apr 6 (Box 1)
  - E. A. Catlin to Walter Scott Copeland 1912 Jun 15 (Box 1)
  - Josephus Daniels to Walter Scott Copeland 1912 Nov 2 (Box 1)
  - Josephus Daniels to Walter Scott Copeland 1912 Nov 12 (Box 1)
  - Josephus Daniels to Walter Scott Copeland 1912 Dec 26 (Box 1)
  - L. F. Stearns to Times Herald Corporation 1913 Jan 7 (Box 1)
  - Henry C. Stuart to Walter Scott Copeland 1913 Mar 22 (Box 1)
  - John S. Bryan to Walter Scott Copeland 1913 Oct 15 (Box 1)
  - Hunter R. Booker to Walter Scott Copeland 1913 Nov 19 (Box 1)
  - T. J. Hundley to Walter Scott Copeland 1913 Dec 3 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1914 Mar 25 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1914 May 2 (Box 1)
  - Eager E. Wood to Walter Scott Copeland 1915 Jun 29 (Box 1)
  - Walter Scott Copeland to R. G. Bickford 1915 Jul 5 (Box 1)
  - Wm. Hodges Mann to Walter Scott Copeland 1915 Jul 9 (Box 1)
  - Jno. G. Pollard to Walter Scott Copeland 1915 Jul 31 (Box 1)
  - W. W. Royall to Walter Scott Copeland 1915 Aug 4 (Box 1)
  - R. E. Gardner to Messers. E. A. Catlin &Co. 1915 Sep 24 (Box 1)
  - O. B. Hill to Walter Scott Copeland 1915 Nov 24 (Box 1)
  - Jesse J. Parkerson to Walter Scott Copeland 1915 Nov 30 (Box 1)
  - E. A. Catlin &Co. to Walter Scott Copeland 1915 Dec 31 (Box 1)
  - J. S. Pender to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Jan 1 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Jan 31 (Box 1)
  - Jno. G. Scott to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Feb 29 (Box 1)
  - H. C. Stuart to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Apr 21 (Box 1)
  - F. Sitterding to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Sep 25 (Box 1)
  - F. Sitterding to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Sep 27 (Box 1)
  - H. C. Stuart to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Oct 27 (Box 1)
  - Charles Friend to Walter Scott Copeland 1916 Dec 23 (Box 1)
  - A. W. Bagley Daniels to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Jan 23 (Box 1)
  - [Roger R. Buning?], Newport News, Va. to The Daily Press, Inc. 1917 Jan 31 (Box 1)
  - Henry W. Holt to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Mar 5 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Mar 10 (Box 1)
  - Gery P. Phinnx to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Apr 8 (Box 1)
  - E. A. Catlin & Co. to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Jun 28 (Box 1)
  - Central Labor Union to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Jul 12 (Box 1)
  - Thomas J. Jones to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Aug 14 (Box 1)
  - Francis W. Lane to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Oct 23 (Box 1)
  - S. P. Moyer to E. W. Christian 1917 Oct 31 (Box 1)
  - H. R. Lane to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Nov 7 (Box 1)
  - Josephus Daniels to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Dec 14 (Box 1)
  - Geo. F. Adams to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Dec 18 (Box 1)
  - Claude A. Swanson to Walter Scott Copeland 1917 Dec 24 (Box 1)
  - A. R. Holderby to Walter Scott Copeland 1918 May 2 (Box 1)
  - Evan R. Chesterman to Walter Scott Copeland 1918 Jun 12 (Box 1)
  - Edward H. O'Hara to Walter Scott Copeland 1918 Aug 8 (Box 1)
  - Josephus Daniels to Walter Scott Copeland 1918 Aug 28 (Box 1)
  - Walter Clarke to Josephus Daniels 1918 Sep 11 (Box 1)
  - W. P. Stuart and I. T. Jacobs to Walter Scott 1918 Oct 1 (Box 1)
  - Claude S. Swanson to Walter Scott Copeland 1918 Dec 19 (Box 1)
  - Thomas S. Martin to Walter Scott Copeland 1919 Feb 14 (Box 1)
  - H. C. Stuart to Walter Scott Copeland 1919 Jun 4 (Box 1)
  - Adelbert Cronkhite to Walter Scott Copeland 1919 Jul 9 (Box 1)
  - C. R. Reiley to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1919 Aug 14 (Box 1)
  - Howard E. Rondthaler to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1919 Sep 13 (Box 1)
  - J. N. Miller to Walter Scott Copeland 1920 Mar 13 (Box 1)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Walter Scott Copeland 1920 Jun 30 (Box 1)
  - Claude A. Swanson to Walter Scott Copeland 1920 Jul 31 (Box 1)
  - Charles Anderson to Walter Scott Copeland 1920 Sep 7 (Box 1)
  - R. W. Montague to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1920 Sep 10 (Box 1)
  - Richard C. L. Moncure to Walter Scott Copeland 1920 Sep 28 (Box 1)
  - F. S. Collier to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Jan 15 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Livezey to Berkley D. Adams 1921 Feb 1 (Box 1)
  - Henry C. Stuart to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Feb 1 (Box 1)
  - Frank Talbott to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Feb 5 (Box 1)
  - John N. Shannahan to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Feb 15 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Forward to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Feb 24 (Box 1)
  - Berkley D. Adams to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Feb 24 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald to Charles M. Schwab 1921 Mar 9 (Box 1)
  - Josephus Daniels to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Mar 11 (Box 1)
  - Newport News Klan to Walter Scott Copeland 1921 Jun 3 (Box 1)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Walter Scott Copeland 1922 Jun 26 (Box 1)
  - Claude A. Swanson to Walters Scott Copeland 1922 Jul 3 (Box 1)
  - R. G. Bickford to S. O. Bland 1922 Jul 11 (Box 1)
  - Geo. B. Christian, Jr. to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1922 Oct 2 (Box 1)
  - James E. Gregg to Walter Scott Copeland 1922 Oct 22 (Box 1)
  - M. K. Duerson to Walter Scott Copeland 1922 Dec 27 (Box 1)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1922 Dec 28 (Box 1)
  - Charles Friend to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Jan 2, 1925 Apr 29 (Box 1)
  - Joseph T. Deal to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Feb 1 (Box 1)
  - Walter Scott Copeland to Langbourne M. Williams 1923 Mar 12 (Box 1)
  - John S. Bryan to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Mar 2 (Box 1)
  - Evan R. Chesterman to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Apr 21 (Box 1)
  - John S. Bryan to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Jun 7 (Box 1)
  - Chas. M. Pace to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Jun 15 (Box 1)
  - Adelbert Cronkhite to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Aug (Box 1)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Aug 20 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Livezey to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Oct 23 (Box 1)
  - W. J. Harahan to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Dec 17 (Box 1)
  - W. J. Harahan to Walter Scott Copeland 1923 Dec 23 (Box 1)
  - Philip W. Murray to Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Jan 8 (Box 1)
  - Ross D. Ford to Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Mar 6 (Box 1)
  - Joseph H. Saunders to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Apr 29 (Box 1)
  - Stuart McGuire to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Jun 11 (Box 1)
  - W. R. Aylett to Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Aug 12 (Box 1)
  - A. M. Hamilton to Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Sep 24 (Box 1)
  - Newport News, Va. to Howard R. Keister 1924 Sep 30 (Box 1)
  - J. A. C. Chandler to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Oct 31 (Box 1)
  - C. Lee Moore to Walter Scott Copeland 1924 Nov 14 (Box 1)
  - S. H. Plummer to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Jan 11 (Box 1)
  - Floyd Holloway to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Jan 20 (Box 1)
  - W. R. Aylett to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Feb 2 (Box 1)
  - W. R. Aylett to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Feb 2 (Box 1)
  - R. N. Watts to Newport News Community Fund 1925 Feb 10 (Box 1)
  - LeRoy Hodges to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Jun 25 (Box 1)
  - Stuart McGuire to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Jul 10 (Box 1)
  - Arthur K. Davis to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Jul 30 (Box 1)
  - LeRoy Hodges to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Aug 7 (Box 1)
  - E. Lee Trinkle to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Aug 7 (Box 2)
  - Arthur W. Goodhand to Newport News, Va. Daily Press 1925 Aug 12 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Aug 22 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Aug 27 (Box 2)
  - R. W. Montague to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep 7 (Box 2)
  - Edward G. Stacy to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep 15 (Box 2)
  - LeRoy Hodges to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep 18 (Box 2)
  - Geo. O. Gruen to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep 19 (Box 2)
  - C. Lee Moore to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep 19 (Box 2)
  - Paul Scarborough to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep 21 (Box 2)
  - J. B. Wall to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep 22 (Box 2)
  - C. H. Edwards to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sept 25 (Box 2)
  - W. A. Land Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Sep (Box 2)
  - Alfred J. Dickinson to Times Herald1925 Oct 1 (Box 2)
  - LeRoy Hodges to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 1 (Box 2)
  - LeRoy Hodges to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 2 (Box 2)
  - T. T. Curtis to J. C. Latimer 1925 Oct 7 (Box 2)
  - Edward G. Story to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 7 (Box 2)
  - Thomas H. West, Jr. to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 10 (Box 2)
  - Wallace Odell to J. C. Latimer 1925 Oct 12 (Box 2)
  - W. C. Bryant to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 13 (Box 2)
  - James B. Cabell to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 17 (Box 2)
  - Wilfred A. Hennessy to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 26 (Box 2)
  - Robert M. Toppan to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 20 (Box 2)
  - L. H. Duncan to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 21 (Box 2)
  - E. L. Taylor to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 21 (Box 2)
  - Howard J. Benchoff to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 27 (Box 2)
  - Richard B. Watrous to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Oct 29 (Box 2)
  - O. P. Von Sweringen to W. J. Harahan 1925 Nov 9 (Box 2)
  - W. J. Harahan to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Nov 12 (Box 2)
  - John H. Doe to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Nov 25 (Box 2)
  - E. C. Hopwood to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Nov 27 (Box 2)
  - Jo Lane Stern to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Dec 2 (Box 2)
  - J. W. Reynolds to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Dec 8 (Box 2)
  - J. B. Wall to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Dec 12 (Box 2)
  - Paul Scarborough to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Dec 14 (Box 2)
  - H. L. Williamson to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Dec 14 (Box 2)
  - G. Guy Via to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Dec 17 (Box 2)
  - Ole Buck to Walter Scott Copeland 1925 Dec 27 (Box 2)
  - Richard H. Edmonds to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Jan 5 (Box 2)
  - H. L. Williamson to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Jan 9 (Box 2)
  - Jo Lane Stern to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Feb 1 (Box 2)
  - C. H. Edwards to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Feb 3 (Box 2)
  - Jno. S. Draper to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Feb 8 (Box 2)
  - Thos. J. Wallner to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Feb 9 (Box 2)
  - Richmond H. Edmonds to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Mar 25 (Box 2)
  - W. E. Rollins to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Apr 7 (Box 2)
  - L. S. Rowe to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Apr 22 (Box 2)
  - Harry Reyner to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 May 28, 1928 Mar 22 (Box 2)
  - W. Russell Bowie to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1926 May 29 (Box 2)
  - J. Lane to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 May 31 (Box 2)
  - C. C. Smith to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Jun 19 (Box 2)
  - A. M. Hamilton to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Jun 22 (Box 2)
  - Stuart G. Gibboney to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Jun 24 (Box 2)
  - R. W. Montague to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Jul 19 (Box 2)
  - Wm. S. Gooch, Jr. to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Aug 9 (Box 2)
  - L. S. Rowe to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Aug 16 (Box 2)
  - H. R. Booker to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Aug 23 (Box 2)
  - C. Vernon Spratley to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Sep 25 (Box 2)
  - Frederic R. Scott to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Nov 12 (Box 2)
  - O. G. Thurlow to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Nov 15 (Box 2)
  - Joseph H. Saunders to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Dec 6 (Box 2)
  - Meta Glass to Walter Scott Glass 1926 Dec 7 (Box 2)
  - Alexander Forward to Walter Scott Copeland 1926 Dec 28 (Box 2)
  - Walter Scott Copeland to Albert C. Ritchie 1927 Jan 3 (Box 2)
  - W. A. R. Goodwin to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Jan 6 (Box 2)
  - Joseph H. Saunders to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Jan 22 (Box 2)
  - Richmond Armstrong to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Mar 15 (Box 2)
  - A. Jacques Garvey to George Mallison 1927 Mar 16 (Box 2)
  - Thomas W. Shelton to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Mar 26 (Box 2)
  - Chas. E. McAllister to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Apr 1 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 May 18 (Box 2)
  - Stuart McGuire to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1927 May 20 (Box 2)
  - E. W. Eberle to Claude A. Swanson 1927 Jun 15 (Box 2)
  - Editor of The Daily Press to T. J. Christian 1927 Jun 21 (Box 2)
  - T. J. Christian to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Jun 20 & 22 (Box 2)
  - J. L. Fering to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Jul 2 (Box 2)
  - Carter Glass to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Aug 24 (Box 2)
  - Louis I. Jaffe to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Aug 25 (Box 2)
  - Donald D. Tuttle to George N. Wise 1927 Aug 25 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Walters Scott Copeland 1927 Sep 29 (Box 2)
  - E. Lee Trinkle to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Oct 21 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Nov 9 (Box 2)
  - Harris Hart to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Nov 10 (Box 2)
  - Louis I. Jaffe to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Nov 28 (Box 2)
  - John P. McConnell to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Nov 28 (Box 2)
  - Walter Scott Copeland to Joseph H. Saunders 1927 Dec 7 (Box 2)
  - Wm. Hodges Mann, Jr. to Walter Scott Copeland 1927 Dec 21 (Box 2)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jan 9 (Box 2)
  - Albert C. Ritchie to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jan 17 (Box 2)
  - T. J. Sims to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jan 29 (Box 2)
  - C. A. Colvin to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Feb 17 (Box 2)
  - Jno. Garland Pollard P. Holt 1928 Feb 17 (Box 2)
  - Jno. Garland Pollard to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Feb 20 (Box 2)
  - Jefferson C. Phillips to Robert P. Holt 1928 Feb 23 (Box 2)
  - J. G. Hiden to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Mar 8 (Box 2)
  - Jno. Garland Pollard to Robert P. Holt 1928 Mar 9 (Box 2)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Mar 12 (Box 2)
  - H. A. C. Chandler to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Mar 16 (Box 2)
  - Frank B. Laurton to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Mar 27 (Box 2)
  - Albert S. Bolling to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Apr 25 (Box 2)
  - Carter Glass to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Apr 26 (Box 2)
  - Carter Glass to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 May 2 (Box 2)
  - Carter Glass to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 May 8 (Box 2)
  - Carter Glass to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 May 14 (Box 2)
  - Alfred S. Dashull to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 May 17 (Box 2)
  - Claude A. Swanson to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 May 22 (Box 2)
  - Carter Glass to Walter Scott Glass 1928 May 23 (Box 2)
  - R. Walton Moore to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 May 28 (Box 2)
  - S. L. Slover to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jun 1 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jun 8 (Box 2)
  - W. R. Van Buren to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jun 11 (Box 2)
  - H. L. Collier to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jun 12 (Box 2)
  - Murray M. McGuire to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jun 12 (Box 2)
  - Rosalie P. Archer to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jun 28 (Box 2)
  - A. F. Harrison to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 16 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 19 (Box 2)
  - J. Keith M. Lee to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 19 (Box 2)
  - Mrs. Frank W. Darling to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 21 (Box 2)
  - Henry C. Kinsey, Jr. to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 21 (Box 2)
  - Wm. C. Styron to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 23 (Box 2)
  - Daniel Grinnan to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 25 (Box 2)
  - S. O. Bland to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 27 (Box 2)
  - Louise Powell to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 27 (Box 2)
  - H. S. G. Tucker to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Jul 30 (Box 2)
  - Stuart McGuire to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Aug 2 (Box 2)
  - A. M. Hamilton to Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Aug 6 (Box 2)
  - T. B. Jones to Elizabeth R. Copeland 1928 Oct 9 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Nov 18 (Box 2)
  - E. A. Alderman to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Dec 26 (Box 2)
  - J. A. C. Chandling to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1928 Dec 28 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 Jan 22 (Box 2)
  - H. S. G. Tucker to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 Feb 13 (Box 2)
  - John P. McConnell to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 Apr 5 (Box 2)
  - Lyon G. Tyler to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 Apr 21 (Box 2)
  - Lyon G. Tyler to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 Apr 23 (Box 2)
  - Lyon G. Tyler to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 May 3 (Box 2)
  - Helen Keller to Walter Scott Copeland 1929 May 21 (Box 2)
  - H. S. G. Tucker to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 Dec 26 (Box 2)
  - Harry F. Byrd to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1929 Dec 30 (Box 2)
  - Ambrose Page to The YMCA of Newport News, Va. 1930 Apr 11 (Box 2)
  - J. P. Fishburn to Mrs. Walter Scott Copeland 1930 May 19 (Box 3)